My name's Liz Fuller and I'm a running coach with Compton Park Runners Club.
我是莉兹·富勒，是康普顿公园跑步俱乐部的跑步教练。
Welcome to my podcast.
欢迎来到我的播客。
If you're thinking about taking up running, I'm here to help.
如果你正在考虑开始跑步，那么我可以帮助你。
There are many training programmes available online which aim to help people build up to running 5 kilometres.
网上有许多训练计划，目标是帮助人们逐渐进步，最后能跑5公里。
Some of them are great and thousands of people of all ages are taking part in 5-kilometre races across the country as a result.
其中一些计划很棒，全国各地成千上万的不同年龄段的人最后都在跑5公里。
People like them because they're easy to follow and don't push them too hard.
人们喜欢这种计划，因为很容易跟着跑下来，而且不会给他们太大压力。
However, they don't work for everyone, especially if you suffer from something like a heart condition or asthma, because they're aimed at people with average fitness and running ability.
然而，这种计划并不适合所有人，尤其是如果你有心脏病、哮喘等疾病，因为这种计划的目标人群是具有平均健康水平和跑步能力的人。
Another thing is that everyone is different, and if you have any specific questions related to your needs, there's no one to provide any answers.
另一个原因是每个人都是不同的，如果你有与你的需求相关的具体问题，没有人能给你提供任何答案。
I have a couple of simple tips I always give to new runners.
我总是会给新入门的跑步者提供几个小建议。
I expect you've been told to run very slowly until your fitness increases -- well, I find that can prevent progress.
我想你应该听说过，在你的体力有所改善之前要跑得非常慢，嗯，我发现这样做会阻碍你进步。
You should run at a speed that feels comfortable, but time yourself and try to run a bit faster each time.
你应该以一种感觉舒服的速度跑，但要给自己计时，并尝试每次都跑得更快一点。
Listening to music can be very helpful -- it takes your mind off things and helps your body get into a rhythm.
听音乐可能会很有帮助，能让你的思绪从其他事情上转移，帮助你的身体进入一种节奏。
I'd say that is better than running with a friend -- especially as most people are competitive and that's not what you want when you're just starting.
我想说，听音乐比和朋友一起跑步效果更好，尤其是因为大多数人都有竞争意识，而刚开始跑步的时候最好不要竞争。
I don't think the time of day is especially important -- some people are better in the evening, while others are morning people --
我认为跑步的时间并不是特别重要，有些人晚上状态更好，有些人早上状态更好，
but you need to be consistent, so aim to train regularly -- twice a week is enough to begin with.
但需要时间保持一致，所以争取做到定期训练，开始时每周跑两次就够了。